<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.maylton.Nocky</id>
  <name>Nocky</name>
  <summary>A native local and YouTube Music player for Linux</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <developer id="io.github.maylton">
    <name>Maylton Fernandes</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
    <p>Nocky is a native GTK4 and libadwaita music player with local album and artist browsing, playlists, liked songs, synchronized lyrics, a real-time audio spectrum, MPRIS integration and optional YouTube Music catalogue/account access.</p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.maylton.Nocky.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>nocky</binary>
  </provides>
  <categories>
    <category>Audio</category>
    <category>Music</category>
    <category>Player</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/maylton/nocky</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/maylton/nocky/issues</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.2.7" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>Ports Noctalia's compact mirrored spectrum behavior to GTK/Cairo, adds 60 Hz logarithmic spectrum processing, gravity falloff, temporal memory, Monstercat smoothing, a zero-warning CI quality gate and a version-synchronized universal installer.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.6" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>Adds a complete first-run setup wizard, conditional synchronized-lyrics wrapping, Noctalia-aware appearance choices and improved Nocky branding in onboarding and About.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.5" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>Introduces a personalized and responsive Home, synchronized online lyrics, categorized search, the Material 3 wavy progress bar, a redesigned adaptive footer with configurable display modes, clickable playback queues, internationalization and multiple performance and visual refinements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.4" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Adds an automatic YouTube Music startup sync and refreshes the library home, album and artist browsing views.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.3" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Adds persistent YouTube library and stream caches, queue prefetching, and high-definition artwork.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.2" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes YouTube runtime discovery and adds a saved startup choice between the local library and YouTube Music.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.1" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Synchronizes the connected YouTube Music library into the native albums, artists, playlists and liked-songs interface.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Adds optional YouTube Music search, account library, liked songs, playlists and GStreamer stream playback.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>First official public beta of Nocky.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
